Tommy Li

Software Engineer

SUMMARY

I enjoy the challenge of solving difficult problems, and I believe the best engineer thing like designers. Whether it's a user interface or an external API, I think about who will be using the things I built and make sure to provide a good user experience. Proven track record of creating and implementing successful front and back-end web applications.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer at OSLabs

Aug 2022 — Present

- Collaborated with a team of developers on a full-stack application where we built an open source application for GraphQL developers
- Implemented a GraphQL IDE using Monaco Editor to allow users to test GraphQL queries, providing a one-stop testing and data-monitoring playground
- Leveraged TypeScript to improve application scalability and make debugging the codebase easier by eliminating type errors prior to runtime
- Integrated Apollo Server to an Express backend to communicate with PostgreSQL database for faster and strongly typed queries and mutations
- Deployed with Docker/AWS EB and setup Cloudfront distribution to direct all incoming traffic to the registered domain name as well as sending all outgoing requests using a secure HTTPS port

Product Developed: Kensa (GraphQL API Monitoring App)

Tech Used: TypeScript | React | Redux Toolkit | Node.js | Express.js | PostgreSQL | GraphQL | Apollo | Chakra UI | Git | AWS | Webpack | Monaco Editor

Software Engineer Toli Development

Jan 2018 — Present

Completed many projects for clients, including building custom full-stack applications and static websites, hosting, doing SEO work for the websites, and using tools like MailChimp to create marketing and handle mailing lists

Recent Projects:

tasksAl (Fullstack Mobile App) – Worked with a team of engineers to develop a task-organization app using React Native and Python/Flask backend that utilizes machine learning to help users boost productivity by generating metrics and recommendations

MonoJStick (Fullstack Web App) – JavaScript one-liner snippets sharing app built with React, Firebase authentication, and Firebase real-time database

SECONEA | Norwalk, CA

June 2021 — Dec 2021

Handled a range of assignments that vary in scope and responsibilities, including utilizing various consultative methods to analyze client needs, ensuring quality in project delivery, and managing project budgets and schedules

CONTACT

(415) 819-8043

tommylidev@gmail.com

ToLi Development

LINKEDIN

GITHUB

LANGUAGES

Javascript

TypeScript

SQL/Postgresgl

Python

HTML/CSS/Sass

SKILLS

React / React Native

Express.js / Node.js

SQL (PostgreSQL)

NoSQL (MongoDB)

AWS

Heroku / Netlify / Vercel

Webpack / Vite

Glt / Github

Flask / Django

Jest / Supertest

Authentication

CERTIFICATION

AWS Certified

Cloud Practitioner

EDUCATION

Cal Poly,

San Luis Obispo

2016 - 2021

Bachelor's degree